Joshua Urban

Project Management expert with over 11 years experience transitioning into a **technical data** role. After graduation from the UNC Data Analytics Bootcamp, focusing on bringing **communication**, **positivity**, and **humor** into Data Analytics and Science. Bringing years of experience and **adaptability** into a new position will allow me to effectively **communicate value** and help push **project success**.

Location

Cary, NC 27513
Open to Remote Work

Contact

984-389-7261 Joshua.R.Urban@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Nox Health, Remote — Project Manager

December 2020 - PRESENT

Led kickoff of company's first Crossfunctional Team (XFT). Provided Project Management and Agile process implementation as shared service.

ndustrial, Raleigh, NC — Software Project Manager

March 2018 - December 2020

Served as Lead Project Manager for Engineering Organization balancing internal products (IOT, ETL, Big Data Management) while interfacing with partnering clients.

rewardStyle (LTK), Dallas, TX — IT Project Manager, Agile Coach

September 2015 - March 2018

Executed company initiatives as a Scrum Master of many different tech teams in a platform driven company. Grew into an Agile Coach role establishing engineering practices and enabling the product team through a major growth phase of the company.

Previous Experience;

- Consulting experience with KPMG (2014-2015) and led the creation of a cloud platform using agile project management for AT&T users.
- Managed major connection projects for **Sabre** (2012-2014) in a Waterfall/Agile methodology.
- Grew to the role of Senior Analyst managing teams for hardware, software, and IT solution projects with **Citibank** (2010-2012).
- Solving complex problems inside the Data Center as a Technician with **The Planet (Softlayer / IBM, 2009-2010).**

EDUCATION

UNC Data Analytics Bootcamp

Exp Completion: November 2021

University of Texas at Arlington

BS of Information Systems, Dec 2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Pandas, ETL, Data Visualization and Storytelling, R, Machine Learning, Javascript, Tableau

PROJECT MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Remote/InPerson Facilitation, Roadmap and Process Workshopping, OKR Implementation, Kanban, Scrum, Iterative Development

PROJECT MANAGEMENT TOOLS

Miro, Jira Cloud and Server, Confluence, Asana, Github, Aha!, Rally, Office Suite, MS Project

PORTFOLIO

github.com/joshuadroid

Thanks for getting this far, Hope you have a great day!